// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    { numb: 1,answer: " 3 ", question: " Which of the following is NOT associated with Computers? ", options: [ " Bit ", " Binary ", " Pencil ", " Mouse ", " Screen "]}, { numb: 2,answer: " 1 ", question: " The first computer which provides storage is ", options: [ " EDSAC ", " EDBAC ", " MARK-I ", " ACE ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 3,answer: " 2 ", question: " Microcomputer hardware consists of three basic categories of physical equipment __________. ", options: [ " keyboard, monitor, hard drive ", " system unit, input/output, memory ", " system unit, input/output, secondary storage ", " system unit, primary storage, secondary storage ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 4,answer: " 2 ", question: " A desktop computer is also known as a – ", options: [ " Palm Pilot ", " PC ", " laptop ", " mainframe ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 5,answer: " 1 ", question: " The benefit of using computers is that ________. ", options: [ " Computers are very fast and can store huge amounts of data ", " Computers provide accurate output even when input is incorrect ", " Computers are designed to be inflexible ", " All of these ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 6,answer: " 3 ", question: " In latest generation computers, the instructions are executed ", options: [ " Parallel only ", " Sequentially only ", " Both sequentially and parallel ", " All of above ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 7,answer: " 1 ", question: " Which of the following are computers that can be carried around easily? ", options: [ " Laptops ", " Supercomputers ", " PCs ", " Minicomputers ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 8,answer: " 1 ", question: " The basic goal of computer process is to convert data into __________. ", options: [ " information ", " tables ", " files ", " graphs ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 9,answer: " 4 ", question: " Computers gather data, which means they allow users to __________ data. ", options: [ " present ", " store ", " output ", " input ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 10,answer: " 4 ", question: " Which of the following is not the major function of a computer? ", options: [ " Processing data into information ", " Storing data or information ", " Gathering data ", " Analysing data or information ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 11,answer: " 1 ", question: " When your computer stops working suddenly, it is referred to as a __________. ", options: [ " crash ", " die ", " death ", " penalty ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 12,answer: " 1 ", question: " First supercomputer developed in India is ", options: [ " PARAM ", " ARYA Bhatt ", " BUDDHA ", " SHIVA ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 13,answer: " 1 ", question: " The benefit of using computers is that ", options: [ " Computers are very fast and can store huge amounts of correct. ", " Computers provide accurate output even when input is incorrect ", " Computers are designed to be inflexible ", " All of the above ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 14,answer: " 4 ", question: " Personal computer is ", options: [ " MC ", " SC ", " YC ", " PC ", " None of these Fundamentals of Computer 13 "]}, { numb: 15,answer: " 2 ", question: " A desktop computer is also known as _________. ", options: [ " Palm Pilot ", " PC ", " laptop ", " mainframe ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 16,answer: " 3 ", question: " A __________ is a small hand-held computer that helps you surf the Web and perform simple tasks. ", options: [ " desktop computer ", " mobile phone ", " notebook computer ", " minicomputer ", " PDA "]}, { numb: 17,answer: " 1 ", question: " A portable, personal computer, small enough to fit on your lap, is called a __________. ", options: [ " notebook computer ", " handheld computer ", " mainframe computer ", " desktop computer ", " super computer "]}, { numb: 18,answer: " 2 ", question: " Computers manipulate data in many ways, and this manipulation is called ", options: [ " upgrading ", " processing ", " batching ", " utilising ", " downloading "]}, { numb: 19,answer: " 4 ", question: " Microprocessor was introduced in which generation of computer? ", options: [ " Second Generation ", " Fourth Generation ", " Both (a) and (b)", " Fourth Generation ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 20,answer: " 2 ", question: " A __________ computer is a large and expensive computer capable of simultaneously processing data for hundreds or thousands of users ", options: [ " server ", " mainframe ", " desktop ", " tablet ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 21,answer: " 4 ", question: " Compatibility in regard to computers refers to ", options: [ " the software doing the right job for the user ", " it being versatile enough to handle the job ", " the software being able to run on the computer ", " software running with other previously installed software ", " None of the above "]}, { numb: 22,answer: " 2 ", question: " The first computers were programmed using ", options: [ " assembly language ", " machine language ", " spaghetti code ", " source code ", " None of the above "]}, { numb: 23,answer: " 2 ", question: " __________ are specially designed computer chips that reside inside other devices, such as your car or your electronic thermostat. ", options: [ " Server ", " Embedded computers ", " Robotic computers ", " Main frames ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 24,answer: " 5 ", question: " Every computer has a(n) __________; many also have __________. ", options: [ " operating system; a client system ", " operating system; instruction sets ", " application programs; an operating system ", " application programs; a client system ", " operating system; application programs "]}, { numb: 25,answer: "5", question: " Computers that are portable and convenient for users who travel are known as ", options: [ " supercomputers ", " planners ", " minicomputers ", " file servers ", " laptops "]}, { numb: 26,answer: " 3 ", question: " The computer’s capability of distinguishing spoken words is called ", options: [ " voice analysis ", " speech acknowledgment ", " voice recognition ", " speech interpretation ", " vocalisation "]}, { numb: 27,answer: " 4 ", question: " What is an embedded system? ", options: [ " A program that comes wrapped in a box. ", " A program that is permanent part of a computer ", " A computer that is part of a larger computer ", " A computer and software system that controls a machine or appliance ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 28,answer: " 2 ", question: " All computers must have ", options: [ " a word processing software ", " an operating system ", " an attached printer ", " a virus checking program ", " None of these 14 Fundamentals of Computer "]}, { numb: 29,answer: "5", question: " Computers excel at ", options: [ " performing the same action(s) over and over the same way. ", " keeping track of large numbers of small details. ", " providing creative solutions to problems. ", " working in fractions of seconds. ", " All of these "]}, { numb: 30,answer: " 4 ", question: " Which of the following refers to the fastest, biggest and most, expensive computers? ", options: [ " Notebooks ", " Personal Computers ", " Laptops ", " Supercomputers ", " PDAs "]}, { numb: 31,answer: "5", question: " Which is not a basic function of a computer? ", options: [ " Accept and process data ", " Accept input ", " Process data ", " Store data ", " Scan text "]}, { numb: 32,answer: " 4 ", question: " Choose the odd one out. ", options: [ " Microcomputer ", " Minicomputer ", " Supercomputer ", " Notebook computer ", " Digital computer "]}, { numb: 33,answer: " 4 ", question: " A computer system that is old and perhaps not satisfactory is referred to as a(n) ", options: [ " Ancient system ", " Historical system ", " Age old system ", " Legacy system ", " Legal system "]}, { numb: 34,answer: " 4 ", question: " The basic goal of a computer process is to convert data into ", options: [ " graphs ", " tables ", " files ", " information ", " diagram "]}, { numb: 35,answer: " 1 ", question: " Analog computer works on the supply of ", options: [ " continuous electrical pulses ", " Electrical pulses but not continuous ", " Magnetic strength ", " Physical strength ", " Natural strength "]}, { numb: 36,answer: " 2 ", question: " Laptops are ", options: [ " Computers used in chemical laboratories ", " Portable, light weight and fit into briefcases ", " Hearing voice recognition system ", " Desktop ", " All of the above "]}, { numb: 37,answer: " 4 ", question: " ________ is not a microcomputer ", options: [ " Desktop computer ", " Tablet PC ", " Handled computer ", " Mainframe computer ", " Laptop "]}, { numb: 38,answer: " 4 ", question: " General purpose computer are used for ", options: [ " Accounting ", " Creating a small database ", " Performs calculation ", " All of the above ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 39,answer: " 2 ", question: " Which is not the example of special purpose computer ? ", options: [ " Automatic Aircraft Landing ", " Word Processor ", " Multimedia computer ", " All of the above ", " None of these "]}, { numb: 40,answer: " 4", question: " Palmtop computer is also known as ", options: [ " Personal computer ", " Notebook computer ", " Tablet PC ", " Handled computer ", " None of these"] },
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];